David Lobo

Software Engineer

Profile

Experienced software engineer with over 10 years experience in development positions. I am passionate about writing quality code and learning new technologies.

Skills

Language: PHP (7yr), Javascript (7yr), AngularJS (1yr), NodeJS(1yr), HTML

(7yr), Objective-C (1yr), Swift (1yr), Java, Python, Flex/Actionscript

Framework/Library: Zend (6Yr), Laravel (2yr), Wordpress (2yr), Doctrine

(2yr), Bootstrap (2yr), jQuery (6yr)

Database: MySQL (9yr)

Software: Sublime(2yr), Git (2yr), Sketch (1yr), Xcode (1yr), Photoshop (4yr)

Server: LAMP, APACHE, AWS, DigitalOcean Linode, Rackspace

Platform: Mac. Windows, Unix/Linux

Work Experience

Feb 2018 - Present

WeAreSweet, London - Web Developer (Contract)

- Built the Brave Productions website, a video subscription site for members to access premium content.
- Implemented new design of donations page, with Stripe Checkout and Infusionsoft integration, for Kigali Genocide Memorial charity.
- Wordpress plugin and custom theme development using PHP, Advanced Custom Fields (ACF) plugin, WP REST API, Sage 9 Theme, Webpack, Javascript, Bootstrap 4, HTML/CSS/SASS.
- Laravel 5/VueJS app to provide a planning board for tasks. Integrated with Basecamp and Slack API.

APR 2017 - DEC 2017

Seedrs, London - *Software Engineer (Contract)*

 Successfully relaunched the Seedrs Alumni Club community platform meeting the target release deadline.

- Features delivered included Single Sign On (SSO), Call To Action system,
 Improvements to filter and search, Custom templates and new pages.
- Wordpress plugin and custom theme development using PHP, Advanced Custom Fields (ACF) plugin, WP REST API, Javascript, HTML/CSS.

APR 2016 - JUN 2016

Nimbletank, London - *PHP/iOS Developer (Contract)*

- Worked on 2 iOS apps 'Crowdsurfparty' and 'WouldLikeToMeet'.
- Working on backend in Symfony, Laravel and NodeJS, integration with Twillio API and Push Notifications using Parse and AWS.
- iOS app bug fixing and small features in Objective-C

JUN 2015 - APR 2016

Freelance - Freelance / Learning new skills

- Designed, built and released 2 native iOS apps on Apple App Store.
- Worked on various projects for clients, including bespoke CMS,
 Prestashop, Wordpress and responsive sites.
- Learnt iOS development fundamentals Objective-C/Swift, Xcode

MAY 2015 - JUN 2015

Apppli, London - Full Stack Developer (Contract)

- Backend REST web services for iOS and Android App, using CakePHP and Laravel.
- Built a custom theme for a client's Wordpress website.

FEB 2014 - MAY 2015

The Reading Room (now Bookstr), London - Senior Web Developer

- Successfully relaunched the entire TheReadingRoom platform on time and to the satisfaction of investors and management team.
- Personally responsible for building a custom CMS application for a high traffic website with large database. Worked directly with the CTO to architect scalable solutions.
- Working with CTO and frontend engineer to build The Reading Room one of the world's fastest growing social discovery platforms for books.

- Using AngularJS, Zend 1.11, Doctrine 2, Bootstrap 3.0, and Twig to build the CMS
- Building new features based on product roadmap, maintenance and bug-fixing post launch

JUN 2010 - JAN 2014

markettiers, London - Web Developer

- Responsible for the overseeing the live video stream for the exclusive european launch event of Nissan Qashqai in 2013.
- Built and maintained a custom video learning platform aimed at Vets for client Bayer Animal Health Webinars.
- Responsible for overseeing the web platform for regular live webTV broadcasts that were critical to the core business of the company.
- Clients including many well known brands such as Nissan, Argos, Bayer, Honda
- Development with LAMP, PHP, Zend Framework, Laravel, Codelgniter, Flex, AS3, Javascript, jQuery, CSS3, HTML
- iOS Development working on Opinion Matters App and Confused App
- Leading the development team when required while helping, mentoring and assigning tasks to junior team members.

NOV 2007 - JUN 2010

I-Tao, Bromley - Junior Developer

- Responsible for maintaining the Integrated Fulfillment System (IFS)
 that powered CDL logistics, a UK based international logistics firm.
- Developing and maintaining web applications using Jython, Java, Python, Webworks, Struts 2, MySQL.
- Worked on building of a package tracking application on Window Mobile that used Java (JVM) for Pearson Publishing mailroom.
- Ongoing support development and support for a large logistics company via telephone and email. Including bug fixing and new development requests.

Education

SEPT 2004 - AUG 2007

University of Kent, Canterbury - Computer Science BSc

2.1 (hons) Computer Science - degree covered many aspects of programming but mainly core Java and OO programming.

SEPT 2001 - AUG 2003

Orpington College, Kent- 3 A Levels

Computing (A), Information and Communications Technology (B), Politics (B)

Contact Details

Location: Eltham, London UK **Email:** david@davidlobo.co.uk

Web: davidlobo.co.uk **Mobile**: 07914362667